

SENIOR FRONTEND ENGINEER II

962-922-1825

vimallakz@gmail.com

49, Ragavendra street, Chennai-63

CAREER OBJECTIVE

SeniorFrontend Developer with 8.5+ years of experience on building leverage modern UI technologies with highly developed skills in scripting languages for many use cases and comfortable to analyze and understand the design under time pressure and presenting myself in a professional manner.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Cogitech Solutions Pvt. Ltd (Tech9)	Sr.Frontend Engineer II	2022 - Present
Ideas2IT Technology Services Pvt. Ltd	Sr.Software Engineer	2017 - 2022
Zoho Corporation Pvt. Ltd	Member Technical staff	2016 - 2017

SKILLS

HTML 5		React js	••••
CSS 3	••••	Angular 7	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$
Javascript		Vue JS	
Typescript		Next JS	
Tailwind CSS		React Native	$\bullet \bullet \circ \circ \circ$
Redux	••••	React Query	
GIT	••••	VS Code	••••

Lashbrook & Emblem ①

2022 - Present

Frontend Team Lead

- Lashbrook & Emblem both provide software for customizing rings with billions of combinations of Inlay / Design patterns / gemstones / profiles / Inside features etc.
- Emblem out on out build on shopify platform to create product & PDP on the fly
- Emblem Builder provides Ring builder Integrations around 102 Shopify partners like
 Bellmans, Mavilo, Atencio, Lamaison, etc
- Payment Gateway integrated with stripe and shopify Payment with Amazon pay, Stripe, Zoho Payments.
- Added more Generic Builder with just sending partner's name changing role and Entire design
- Product uses Amazon Image service / Lambda / S3 / Cloudfront / Log Rocket.

Goedit Graphics D Frontend Team Lead

2020 - 2022

- Frontend Team Lead
- Software allows users with no design skills to create custom graphics for your school and athletic department by changing the colors, text, and images. It's quick, easy, and affordable.
- It uses React-Konva on top konva.js to create customized templates with so many options Lock layer / Replace image layer / Add Video and generate Gif.
- It has Zoho and stripe payment Integrations and also provides support for offline option to enable your subscription
- Software provides admin role to create new subscription plan on the go and publish to customers in mean time
- Product Uses React / graphql / Digital ocean spaces / Screen recording

Intelligent Talent Acquisition

2017-2018

Junior Software Engineer

- resume parser system (TextKernel) to add candidates for the recruiting process.
- Integrating Text kernel and Add candidate manually to Single page
- Integrating Query based Profile filter to filter profiles for matching openings.
- Integrating google docs viewer for view candidate Resume and his certificates.
- Established dynamic ACL Implementation for the UI elements.
- Implemented Chart(React-highcharts) for the dashboard for the visualization of resume data.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Father's Name Janarthanan.N

Date of Birth 22-09-1994

Marital Status Married

Linguistic English, Tamil

Hobbies Watching & Playing Cricket / Reading Novels

Education(UG) B.E ECE

Social Information